Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Part II - Correspondence
  - APRIL 1979
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Continued discussion re. sale of JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR - Sesonske concerned about preserving J.R.'s papers - Letter from Anne explaining sources of J.R.'s income Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Sesonske, Alexander (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - MAY-AUGUST 1979
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Dido interest in J.R. project CHRISTINE - Manuscripts left by J.R. being typed, discussions re. their possible publication - Anne duplication of J.R. comments on Renoir painting LE CHASSEUR - Discussions re. filming of JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR, directed by Jeanne Moreau - Negotiations over film rights to CAPITAINE GEORGES - Negotiations with Flammarion re. GENEVIEVE - Dido finds J.R. manuscipt LANCELOT Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Moreau, Jeanne * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * GENEVIEVE (project) * Truffaut, Francois * LANCELOT (project) * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - SEPTEMBER-DECEMBER 1979
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - J.R. retrospective planned in Florence in October - GENEVIEVE being edited - Continued discussions, preparation re. J.R-OEUVRES - Copy of CAPITAINE GEORGES contract Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Caron, Leslie * GENEVIEVE (project) * JEAN RENOIR-OEUVRES DE CINEMA * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Bogdanovich, Peter * Truffaut, Francois * Braunberger, Pierre (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - UNDATED 1970-1979
    - Correspondence with Beylie: question re. Denise Tual and editing of LA CHIENNE Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Ryan, Robert * Moreau, Jeanne * McBride, Joseph * Beylie, Claude * CHIENNE, LA * Tual, Denise (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - JANUARY-MAY 1980
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Continued preparation for J.R.-OEUVRES, discussions of MAGNIFICAT, LANCELOT - GENEVIEVE published - Ongoing legal dispute with Braunberger over money due to J.R. estate - Dido refuses Faulkner desire to publish J.R.'s letters - Renewed interest, difficulty finding U.S. publisher for J.R. novels - Discussion re. Andre Derain and scenario DAVUKE N'BONGO Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * JEAN RENOIR-OEUVRES DE CINEMA * GENEVIEVE (project) * Truffaut, Francois * Sesonske, Alexander * Magnin, Rabbi Edgar * Gauteur, Claude * Narboni, Jean * Braunberger, Pierre * Derain, Andre * MAGNIFICAT (project) * LANCELOT (project) * DAVUKE N'BONGO (project) (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - JUNE-NOVEMBER 1980
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - J.R. retrospective planned Paris, October - Sesonske book on J.R. published - L'AVANT-SCENE publishes special issue on J.R., Dido's corrections - Continued discussion of various J.R. writings for publication - Sesonske researching THE RIVER Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * JEAN RENOIR-OEUVRES DE CINEMA * Sesonske, Alexander * Godden, Rumer * RIVER, THE * ORVET (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - DECEMBER 1980-MARCH 1981
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Dido against Madame Spaak porposal of GRANDE ILLUSION remake with Brando - Braunberger dispute continued - Dido gives permission to name Dieppe Cultural Center after Jean Renoir. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Braunberger, Pierre * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * Truffaut, Francois * Brando, Marlon (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - APRIL-SEPTEMBER 1981
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Braunberger issues continued - Discussion re. donation of J.R. papers to UC Santa Barbara, Harvard, French Cinematheque, or Archives Nationales Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Simenon, Georges * Arnoul, Francoise * Godden, Rumer * Viry-Babel, Roger (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - OCTOBER 1981-FEBRUARY 1982
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Sesonske finds print of LE TOURNOI, Dido seeks to obtain it and copy of DIRECTION D'ACTEUR - Discussions with Sesonske re. publication of J.R. letters by Gallimard - Anne seeks help from Coppola re. piracy problems - Copy of J.R. honorary doctorate from UC - Publication of J.R.-OEUVRES DE CINEMA INEDITES - Discussion of CAROLA influence on Truffaut's DERNIER METRO Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * TOURNOI, LE * Sesonske, Alexander * Coppola, Francis Ford * Caron, Leslie * JEAN RENOIR-OEUVRES DE CINEMA * Truffaut, Francois * CAROLA * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - MARCH-JULY 1982
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Continued preparation of J.R. letters for publication - Dido receives restored print of LE TOURNOI - J.R. retrospective planned at Berkeley in June Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Sesonske, Alexander * TOURNOI, LE * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - AUGUST 1982-JANUARY 1983
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Continued preparation of J.R. letters for publication - Proposal for French documentary on J.R. written by Daniel Serceau - Sesonske tells Makavejev story about J.R. scandal in Yugoslavia, 1971 - Anne and Dido discuss handing J.R. affairs to Nicole Jouve in Paris and Alain Renoir in USA - Anne note on J.R., Makavejev, Spaak - Discussions re. video distribution rights to LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - Old J.R. interview found Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Sesonske, Alexander * Truffaut, Francois * Serceau, Daniel * Makavejev, Dusan * Caron, Leslie * Spaak, Charles * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - FEBRUARY-JUNE 1983
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Continued attempts to obtain prints of old J.R. films - Gallimard refuses LETTRES D'AMERIQUES, Flammarion hesistant - CAPORAL EPINGLE video issues continued - Dido obtaining copies of DIRECTION D'ACTEURS and WOMAN ON THE BEACH - La Presse de la Renaissance to publish LETTRES D'AMERIQUES, copy of contract Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * Caron, Leslie * Sesonske, Alexander * Simenon, Georges * Truffaut, Francois (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - APRIL-OCTOBER 1984
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Correspondence with Celia Bertin - Copy of review of LETTRES D'AMERIQUES by Claude Gauteur - Cinematheque Munich plans J.R. retrospective for fall - Continued discussion re. U.S. publication of LETTRES D'AMERIQUES, disagreement between Anne and Sesonske - Braunberger corrections to LETTRES D'AMERIQUES - Dido searches for J.R.'s TERRE DES HOMMES treatment - Disney to remake BOUDU - Death of Truffaut Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Bazin, Janine * Bertin, Celia * Sesonske, Alexander * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES * Simenon, Georges * Braunberger, Pierre * Saint-Exupery, Antoine de * BOUDU SAUVE DES EAUX * Truffaut, Francois (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - JULY 1983-MARCH 1984
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Discussions re. U.S. publication of LETTRES D'AMERIQUES - Discussions re. U.S. distribution rights to FRENCH CANCAN, possibility of adding letters from Americans Daniel Serceau plan to study French receipts of J.R. films 1950-1960 - Re. LETTRES D'AMERIQUE IN France: continued preparations, corrections, publication, reactions - Dido refuses theatrical adaptation of LA GRANDE ILLUSION Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Truffaut, Francois * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES * Sesonske, Alexander * FRENCH CANCAN * Serceau, Daniel * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * Saint-Exupery, Antoine de (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - NOVEMBER 1984-SEPTEMBER 1985
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Saint-Exupery exhibit at French National Archives includes taped correspondence with J.R. - Bessy, Beylie preparing book on J.R. - NY, LA screenings of "original" FRENCH CANCAN - Plan for video distribution of BOUDU Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Saint-Exupery, Antoine de * Bessy, Maurice * FRENCH CANCAN * BOUDU SAUVE DES EAUX (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - OCTOBER-DECEMBER 1985
    - Correspondence between Dido and Anne - Jean-Pierre Pagliano preparing book on UNE PARTIE DE CAMPAGNE Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * PARTIE DE CAMPAGNE, UNE * Serceau, Daniel (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - 1986
    - Letter re. forthcoming book on J.R. by Roger Viry-Babel - UCLA obtains print of THE SOUTHERNER Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Viry-Babel, Roger * SOUTHERNER, THE (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - 1987-1988
    - Sesonske considering U.S. publication of Renoir letters - Photocopies of old J.R. letters - Response from Anne de Saint Phalle - Braunberger concerned about Autant-Lara book Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Caron, Leslie * LETTRES D'AMERIQUES * Sesonske, Alexander * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * Braunberger, Pierre * Autant-Lara, CLaude * Godden, Rumer (Box 37, Folder 2)